[
  {
    "question": "1. What is Git ?",
    "answer": "Git is a distributed version control system: tracking changes in any set of files, usually used for coordinating work among programmers collaboratively developing source code during software development. Its goals include speed, data integrity, and support for distributed, non-linear workflows (thousands of parallel branches running on different systems)."
  },
  {
    "question": "2. What is a version control system (VCS)?",
    "answer": " A VCS keeps track of the contributions of the developers working as a team on the projects. They maintain the history of code changes done and with project evolution, it gives an upper hand to the developers to introduce new code, fixes bugs, and run tests with confidence that their previously working copy could be restored at any moment in case things go wrong"
  },
  {
    "question": "3. What is a git repository?",
    "answer": " A repository is a file structure where git stores all the project-based files. Git can either stores the files on the local or the remote repository."
  },
  {
    "question": "4. What does git clone do?",
    "answer": " The command creates a copy (or clone) of an existing git repository. Generally, it is used to get a copy of the remote repository to the local repository."
  },
  {
    "question": "5. What does the command git config do?",
    "answer": " The git config command is a convenient way to set configuration options for defining the behavior of the repository, user information and preferences, git installation-based configurations, and many such things. "
  },
  {
    "question": "6. What is a conflict?",
    "answer": " Git usually handles feature merges automatically but sometimes while working in a team environment, there might be cases of conflicts such as: 1. When two separate branches have changes to the same line in a file 2. A file is deleted in one branch but has been modified in the other. "
  },
  {
    "question": "7. What is the functionality of git ls-tree?",
    "answer": " This command returns a tree object representation of the current repository along with the mode and the name of each item and the SHA-1 value of the blob"
  },
  {
    "question": "8. What does git status command do?",
    "answer": " git status command is used for showing the difference between the working directory and the index which is helpful for understanding git in-depth and also keep track of the tracked and non-tracked changes"
  },
  {
    "question": "9. What does git add command do?",
    "answer": " This command adds files and changes to the index of the existing directory."
  },
  {
    "question": "10. How will you create a git repository? ",
    "answer": " Have git installed in your system. Then in order to create a git repository, create a folder for the project and then run git init. Doing this will create a .git file in the project folder which indicates that the repository has been created"
  },
  {
    "question": "11. What is branch?",
    "answer": " A branch is nothing but a separate version of the code."
  },
  {
    "question": "12. What is pull request?",
    "answer": " This process is done when there is a need to put a developer's change into another person's code branch. "
  },
  {
    "question": "13. Can you tell the difference between Git and GitHub?",
    "answer": " Git is a distributed version control system installed on local machines which allow developers to keep track of commit histories and supports collaborative work. Github is a cloud-based source code repository developed by using git."
  },
  {
    "question": "14. What is a commit message? ",
    "answer": " The command that is used to write a commit message is “git commit -a”. Now explain about -a flag by saying -a on the command line instructs git to commit the new content of all tracked files that have been modified. Also, mention you can use “git add <file>” before git commit -a if new files need to be committed for the first time."
  },
  {
    "question": "15. What is a 'conflict' in git?",
    "answer": " Git can handle on its own most merges by using its automatic merging features. There arises a conflict when two separate branches have made edits to the same line in a file, or when a file has been deleted in one branch but edited in the other. Conflicts are most likely to happen when working in a team environment."
  }
]
